our plans. They shall be carried out to the day.
Forward, comrades. Long live the windmill. Long live Animal Farm.
>> Chapter seven.
>> It was a bitter winter.
The stormy weather was followed by sleet and snow and then by a hard frost which
did not break till well into February.
The animals carried on as best they could with the rebuilding of the windmill
well knowing that the outside world was watching them and that the envious human beings would
rejoice and triumph if the mill were not finished on time.
Out of spite, the human beings pretended not to believe that it was Snowball who
had destroyed the windmill.
They said that it had fallen down because the walls were too thin.
The animals knew that this was not the case.
Still, it had been decided to build the walls 3 ft thick this time instead of 18
in as before which meant collecting much larger quantities of stone.
For a long time, the quarry was full of snowdrifts and nothing could be done.
Some progress was made in the dry frosty weather that followed, but it was cruel
work, and the animals could not feel so hopeful about it as they had felt before.
They were always cold and usually hungry as well.
Only Boxer and Clover never lost heart.
Squealer made excellent speeches on the joy of service and the dignity of labor,
but the other animals found more inspiration in Boxer's strength and his
never-failing cry of, "I will work harder."
In January, food fell short.
The corn ration was drastically reduced, and it was announced that an extra
potato ration would be issued to make up for it.
Then it was discovered that the greater part of the potato crop had been frosted
in the clamps, which had not been covered thickly enough.
The potatoes had become soft and discolored, and only a few were edible.
For days at a time, the animals had nothing to eat but chaff and mangels.
Starvation seemed to stare them in the face.
It was vitally necessary to conceal this fact from the outside world.
Emboldened by the collapse of the windmill, the human beings were
inventing fresh lies about Animal Farm.
Once again, it was being put about that all the animals were dying of famine and
disease, and that they were continually fighting among themselves and had
resorted to cannibalism and infanticide.
Napoleon was well aware of the bad results that might follow if the real
facts of the food situation were known, and he decided to make use of Mr.
Whymper to spread a contrary impression.
Hitherto, the animals had had little or no contact with Whymper on his weekly visits.
Now, however, a few selected animals, mostly sheep, were instructed to remark
casually in his hearing that rations had been increased.
In addition, Napoleon ordered the almost empty bins in the store shed to be
filled nearly to the brim with sand, which was then covered up with what
remained of the grain and meal.
On some suitable pretext, Whymper was led through the store shed and allowed
to catch a glimpse of the bins.
He was deceived and continued to report to the outside world that there was no
food shortage on Animal Farm.
Nevertheless, towards the end of January, it became obvious that it would
be necessary to procure some more grain from somewhere.
In these days, Napoleon rarely appeared in public, but spent all his time in the
farmhouse, which was guarded at each door by fierce-looking dogs.
When he did emerge, it was in a ceremonial manner with an escort of six
dogs who closely surrounded him and growled if anyone came too near.
Frequently, he did not even appear on Sunday mornings, but issued his orders
through one of the other pigs, usually Squealer.
One Sunday morning, Squealer announced that the hens, who had just come in to
lay again, must surrender their eggs.
Napoleon had accepted, through Whymper, a contract for 400 eggs a week.
The price of these would pay for enough grain and meal to keep the farm going
till summer came on and conditions were easier.
When the hens heard this, they raised a terrible outcry.
They had been warned earlier that this sacrifice might be necessary, but had
not believed that it would really happen.
They were just getting their clutches ready for the spring sitting, and they
protested that to take the eggs away now was murder.
For the first time since the expulsion of Jones, there was something resembling a rebellion.
Led by three young black Minorca pullets, the hens made a determined
effort to thwart Napoleon's wishes.
Their method was to fly up to the rafters and there lay their eggs, which
smashed to pieces on the floor.
Napoleon acted swiftly and ruthlessly.
He ordered the hens' rations to be stopped and decreed that any animal
giving so much as a grain of corn to a hen should be punished by death.
The dogs saw to it that these orders were carried out.
For 5 days the hens held out, then they capitulated and went back to their nesting boxes.
Nine hens had died in the meantime.
Their bodies were buried in the orchard and it was given out that they had died